Sadegh Bashiri

Java Back-End Developer

<u>Sadegh.Bashiri.dev@gmail.com</u> linkedin +989364665266 github

Summary

Backend Developer with more than 3 years of practical experience in Java language implementing range of business logics. Successfully implementation a user management system for the insurance company, resulting in a streamlined and secure user authentication process. Have worked in agile environments with teammates from 5 to 15 people. led re-architecture of key platform to increase over 60 percent of requests per second in latest position. Have optimized and refactored code base from scratch to increase 45 performance boost in Tamin project.

Experience



Java Backend Developer

Tamin (ICT & Management Consultancy) · Full-time

Jan 2021 - Present · 2 yrs 5 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Responsibilities:

- Led the transition to paperless by implementing an authentication and authorization system. 30% reduction in client visits to insurance branches and 10% reduction in administrative costs.
- Mechanization of the authorization system for users within the insurance organization at the branches at the national level. Reduced cost of labor by 40%
- Develop and maintain Java EE applications for user-management in an insurance company, contributing to the successful implementation of 15+ OAuth features.
- Designed and Deployed secure authentication and authorization mechanisms using Java EE technologies, resulting in a 20% reduction in unauthorized access attempts.



Java Backend Developer

Maktab Sharif · Full-time

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021 · 6 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Learned the Spring Boot framework in 6 months.
- Carrying out more than 20 projects based on Java core, Spring MVC, Spring Boot during the bootcamp.
- Assisted in the development and maintenance of Java applications using Spring frameworks, contributing to the successful completion of 20+ development tasks within assigned deadlines.



Software Technical Support Expert

ArianSystem · Full-time

Jul 2019 - Mar 2020 · 9 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Analyzed and optimize business processes within the BPMS, resulting in a 20% increase in process efficiency and a 15% reduction in turnaround time.
- Generated comprehensive reports using SQL Server reporting tools, presenting statistical insights and trends to stakeholders, ensuring data accuracy with a 98% validation success rate.
- Documentation and Knowledge Sharing: Created documentation, knowledge base articles, and FAQs to help customers troubleshoot common issues related to SQL Server.

Software Technical Support Expert

ShahreNovin · Full-time

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019 · 1 yr 8 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Coached (mentored, pair programing) 2 new comes for better onboarding process for over 3 months.
- Supervisor of the support unit for 1 year.
- Collaborated with development teams to escalate and resolve complex technical issues, ensuring that 95% of critical issues are resolved within 48 hours.



Software Technical Support Expert

Faratahlilgaran Varjavand · Full-time

Sep 2015 - Jan 2018 · 2 yrs 5 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Analyze and optimize SQL queries to enhance database performance, resulting in a 15% improvement in query execution time and reducing server response time by 20%.
- Analysis, design and implementation of integrated financial information and management software.
- Customized and configured the BPMS to meet specific business requirements for more than 50 clients and 90% client satisfaction rate.
- Assist in the integration of the BPMS with other systems and technologies, successfully integrating the BPMS with over 20 third-party applications and success in data synchronization.
- Assisted customers in setting up and configuring SQL Server, including installation, database creation, and user management.

Education

Islamic Azad University of Kermanshah

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

Sep 2010 - Oct 2014

Skills

Java Core

JavaEE

Spring (MVC, Boot, Security, Data, etc)

Hibernate

MySQL

Angular

Git

REST APIs

Swagger